Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Good morning, Shinji. How are you?
I'm getting used to it.
I think it's not bad.
That's good.
Have you memorized the positions
of all the Eva emergence points,
emergency power junctions, armament
buildings, and recovery zones?
I think so.
Then, I'll review it one more time.
Normally the Eva runs off electricity
provided by an umbilical cable.
In emergencies, it can switch to
an internal battery,
with an active life of one minute at full power,
and no more than five minutes in
the minimal activity gain mode.
This is the limitations of
our current technology.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Now let's continue from where we left off
yesterday. We'll initiate Induction Mode.
Position the target in the center,
then switch "on".
Calm down. Position the target in the center.
Switch...
Next!
But I'm surprised that Shinji
agreed to pilot it.
He simply does what he's told to do.
Maybe that's his way of getting through life.
Target in the center, pull the switch.
Target in the center...
EPISODE THREE
THE SILENT PHONE
And now, from Tokyo we go to
Miss Natsuko Shinohara in Matsuzaki.
Good morning, this is Shinohara.
Guess what?
Today I'm in Matsuzaki in West lzu
for a little scuba diving!
Today's forecast is sunny, with an
estimated high of 32 degrees C.
Miss Misato, it's morning already.
We have hot days all year now,
but we used to have four seasons:
I just got back from night duty.
Spring, Summer, Fall and Winter.
I don't have to go to work until this
evening, so please, let me sleep.
We never see snow these days,
instead, due to the recent warmth,
I see. I'll go.
aquatic life has been coming back
little by little.
Hey, is today Thursday?
As you dive into the sea you can
clearly see an abundance of fish.
Take the burnable trash
to the garbage, please.
Yes, Ma'am.
It makes me think of catching some
for tonight's dinner.
So, are you adjusting to school?
Yeah.
Oh, okay. See you later.
Although the town brings back sad
memories, this is a hot diving spot.
I'll see you later.
Yes? Hello?
Oh, it's you, Ritsuko.
How's it going? Are you getting along
with your boyfriend?
Boyfriend?
Oh, you mean Shinji.
Well, he transferred into school two
weeks ago and he hasn't changed.
No one ever calls him.
Calls him?
Well, since I figured he'd need one,
I gave him a cell phone a while back.
I don't think he's ever used it though,
or received any calls.
I'm not sure, but I don't think
he has any friends.
Well, I would guess that Shinji's not
the sort who makes friends easily.
Do you know the fable of the
"Hedgehog's Dilemma"?
Hedgehog? You mean those animals
with the spiny hair?
Even though a hedgehog may wish
to get close to another hedgehog,
the closer they get, the more they
injure each other with their spines.
It's the same with some humans.
Shinji is probably afraid of pain and has
become a coward somewhere in his heart.
Well, he'll eventually learn that growing up
means getting closer to people
and distancing them,
finding a distance where you can avoid
hurting each other too much.
What's up, class rep?
Class Daybook
Did you give him the printout
I gave you yesterday?
What? Well...
Well, there wasn't anybody home
at Toji's place.
Aida, you're good friends
with Suzuhara, right?
He's been absent for two weeks.
Aren't you worried?
Do you suppose he's been seriously injured?
What? In that robot incident?!
The television report said
that nobody was injured!
No way, you saw the explosion site
on Mount Takanosu, didn't you?
Not only were Iruma and
Komatsu dispatched,
they brought in troops from
Misawa and Kyushu.
There had to have been well over
a couple dozen people injured,
and even some killed.
Toji!
Suzuhara!
Wow, has the class population
dropped or what?
They've all evacuated and
transferred to other schools.
After all, no one wants to stay after
that fierce battle inside the city.
Yeah, you're probably the only one
who's actually enjoyin' the chance
to see a real war.
I suppose so.
So where have you been, Toji?
You were gone for so long.
Did you get caught in the crossfire
or something?
My kid sister did.
She was crushed under a pile of debris.
She survived, but she's been
in the hospital ever since.
Both my pop and gramps work at the lab,
and there's no way they can
leave their posts right now.
So, if I ain't with her, she's all alone
at the hospital.
Man, that robot's pilot was plain awful!
I'm downright pissed off!
What the hell's the point of
our own guy wreckin' the city?
Oh, about the pilot, have you heard the
rumor about the new transfer student?
Transfer student?
Him, over there.
He transferred here while you were absent.
He came right after the incident.
Don't you think that's odd?
All rise!
And so, humankind was about to face
its greatest trial.
In the last year of the 20th century,
the massive meteor from space slammed
into the continent of Antarctica.
The continent's ice cap was melted
almost instantaneously.
The water level of the oceans rose,
the Earth was thrown off its axis,
and abnormal weather patterns threatened
the lives of all living things.
Several thousand species and half of the
world's population were lost for eternity.
That was the so-called "Second lmpact".
The survivors still had to live through the hell
of worldwide economic collapse,
ethnic conflicts, and civil wars.
Is it true that you're the pilot of that robot? Y/N
However, it has been fifteen years since then.
In only fifteen years,
we have restored ourselves.
This is certainly proof of the human race's
resilience, but even more so,
It's true, isn't it?
it is the fruit of the blood, sweat and tears
your fathers and mothers have
dedicated to this cause.
What?!
Really?! Oh, wow! Cool!
I lived in Nebukawa at the time,
which is underwater now...
Really, the new student was?
Hey, you guys!
We're still in class, you know!
Sit down now!
Aw, you're always so bossy!
It's okay, it's okay!
It's not okay!
Well...
Hey, how were you chosen?
Were there any tests?
Weren't you scared?
What's the cockpit look like?
Well, that's all secret.
Hey, what's the name of the robot?
I don't know much, but everyone
calls it Eva or Unit 01.
Eva?
And what's its ultimate attack?
Some kind of knife.
It vibrates... An ultra-sonic wave...
That's amazing! You're the pride
of the school!
Yeah, right! Cool!
And thus...
Oh...
That's all for today.
Ikari, where do you live?
All rise! Bow!
Hey, you guys, why don't you at least
show some manners at the end?
Sorry, transfer student,
but I've gotta beat you up!
I won't feel right until I've smacked you.
Sorry, his little sister was injured
in the incident the other day.
Well, there you have it.
I'm not piloting it by choice either.
An emergency call.
I'll go on ahead.
A special state of emergency
has been declared
for the Kanto and Chubu regions
surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their
designated shelters immediately.
Repeating...
The target has been sighted by our cameras.
It's already penetrated into
our territorial waters.
All personnel, assume
battle stations, Level One.
Roger, prepare for anti-aircraft interception.
New Tokyo-3 transforming
to battle formation.
Initiate accommodation of the central block.
Accommodation of central block
and the first through seventh districts
has been completed.
Notification of the government and other
related ministries, completed.
Target is still advancing.
Present operational rate of anti-aircraft
interception: 48%.
What's the status of noncombatants
and civilians?
We've already received reports that
the evacuation has been completed.
Underground Shelter 334
Disaster Prevention Department, Tokyo-3
Total Floor Space
Maximum Capacity
Attention, elementary school and
junior high school students.
Please form groups with
your individual classes.
At noon today, a special emergency declaration was issued for the Kanto and Central regions centering on the Tokai area.
Details will be reported as they come in.
Not again!
Just text messages again?
It's news censorship. They won't
show any of it to us civilians.
Even though it's an incredible event.
The fourth Angel would show up
while Commander lkari is away.
It's a lot sooner than we expected.
The last time they gave us
a fifteen year break.
This time it's been only three weeks.
They never care about
our convenience, do they?
They're the type we women hate the most.
It's a waste of the taxpayers' money.
The committee is demanding that
we dispatch an Evangelion again.
Those pesky bastards.
Even if they hadn't asked for it,
I'd have dispatched it anyway.
Entry procedure initiated.
LCL oxygenated.
Releasing airlock.
Why am I piloting this thing again,
even though my father's not here?
Even though I got beat up?
Hey, I need to talk to you,
privately, you know?
What for?
Just give me a second, okay?
Well, okay.
Class rep!
What?
We both hafta go to the john!
You were supposed to use the bathroom
before you came here.
So, what's this about?
I've got to see it, at least once in my life.
You mean the battle up there?
Nobody knows when the enemy
will come the next time.
Kensuke, are you serious?
If we let this opportunity escape us,
we may lose it forever!
Please, help me unlock the gate.
But you'll get killed if you go out there.
You don't know if that'll happen,
even if we stay here.
If I could be killed anyway,
I'd rather see it first.
Idiot. What do you think Nerv's for?
And what is Nerv's most important weapon?
It's the robot the new kid pilots.
He protected us the other day,
but you hit him pretty hard. Twice!
If he refuses to pilot the robot,
we're all going to die.
Don't you have a duty to watch him fight?
Ah, whatever.
You sure are upfront about what you want,
ain't you?
Shinji, are you ready to head out?
Yes.
Listen to me. Neutralize the enemy's AT field,
then fire a volley from the pallet gun.
Do it just like we practiced.
Can you handle that?
Yes.
Launch!
Cool! All my efforts really paid off!
Oh! This is what I've been waiting for!
There it is!
The AT field has been deployed.
Target in the center, pull the switch.
Do it just as planned, okay, Shinji?
Right.
You idiot! You hid the enemy
with your own smoke!
What the hell?! He's already losing!
It's all right.
I'm sending you a spare rifle.
Take it!
Shinji? Shinji?
Oh, man!
Being beaten up must have
really messed him up.
Shut up!
The umbilical cable's been severed!
Eva has switched to its internal
battery power source.
4 minutes, 53 seconds
of activation remaining.
It's comin' this way!
Shinji, are you all right? Shinji!
Damage report?
No problems detected. He can make it.
Shinji's classmates?
What are they doing there?
Why won't he fight?
Because we're here?
He can't move because of us!
Unit 01 activation time remaining,
3 minutes 28 seconds.
Shinji, let them into the cockpit!
Once you've got them,
make a temporary retreat.
We'll regroup!
You think you can allow unauthorized
civilians into the entry plug?!
I'm authorizing it.
You're exceeding your authority,
Captain Katsuragi!
Unit 01's remaining activation time,
3 minutes.
Hold Eva on your current commands
and eject the entry plug. Hurry up!
You two! Get in! Hurry!
What the... It's water?
My camera! My camera!
Abnormal conditions occurring
in the nervous system!
Of course. It's because you've allowed
two foreign bodies into the plug.
They're introducing noise
in the nerve impulse systems!
Now! Retreat!
Recovery route 34, retreat to
the east side of the mountain.
Hey, new kid, she said, "Retreat!"
I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away.
New kid!
I mustn't run away!
Progressive Knife engaged!
Obey my orders, Shinji! You've got to retreat!
Shinji!
That idiot...
Unit 01, activation time
remaining, 30 seconds!
28... 27...
26... 25...
14... 13...
12... 11...
10... 9...
8... 7...
6... 5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Eva Unit 01, activation ceased.
The target is completely silent.
It's been three days.
You mean, since we were chewed out?
No, since he stopped comin' to school.
Who's "he"?
The new kid, the new kid.
I wonder what he's been doin' since then?
Are you worried about him?
No, not exactly worried.
Toji, for someone who's so tactless,
you're pretty stubborn.
If you had apologized to him back then,
you wouldn't have had to agonize
over it for three days.
Here, this is the new kid's phone number.
If you're so worried, why don't you call him?
To Be Continued
PREVIEW
Unable to overcome his feelings,
Shinji even runs away from Misato.
But the organization brings him
back without hesitation.
There were no kind words waiting for him.
Next Evangelion:
"Rain, After Running Away"
And of course, I'll give you lots
of fan service next time too!
RAIN, AFTER RUNNING AWAY